motilo.com 2015-04-08

# Privacy Policy | Motilo

Motilo Limited is committed to ensuring that your personal information is used properly and is kept securely. This Privacy and Cookies Policy explains how we will collect and use your personal information. When you submit personal information on the website you will see a 'Data Protection Notice' that will provide additional information about how your personal information will be used by Motilo Limited.

**By entering your details in the fields requested and pressing 'Submit', you are consenting to the processing of your information by Motilo and its agents in accordance with this Privacy and Cookies Policy.**

## Data Controller

Any personal information that you provide on this website is controlled by Motilo Limited.

Motilo Limited is registered as a data controller with the Information Commissioner under reference: 00040194085.

Motilo Limited is a company registered in England and Wales with company number 06629594. Our registered office is at 7 Howick Place, London SW1P 1BB.

If you have any queries about the information we hold about you, please contact our Data Protection Officer, Snjezana Maclean, [data@motilo.com](mailto:data@motilo.com), whom you may write to at the address above.

## Collection of your personal information

When you visit, register or order products or services on the website, you may be asked to provide us with information about yourself. You may also provide personal information to us when you contact us by email, telephone or letter. We may collect information about you from documents that are available to the public, such as the electoral register, or from third parties such as credit reference agencies. When you provide personal information to us or we collect personal information from other sources, we will treat that information in accordance with this Privacy and Cookies Policy.

## Use and storage of your personal information

We will use personal information provided by you or gathered by Motilo Limited for the following purposes:

  * to process and respond to requests, enquiries and complaints received from you
  * to provide products and services requested by you
  * to communicate with you about services provided to you
  * to process payments
  * to update our records
  * to analyse trends and profiles
  * for audit purposes
  * to carry out customer satisfaction research or provide you with the opportunity to enter into surveys, contests, sweepstakes and other promotions
  * to prevent or detect fraud
  * to recommend products and services that we believe will be of interest to you
  * to enable third parties to carry out any of the purposes above on our behalf

## Information Security

We store your personal information in limited access servers, and will maintain commercially reasonable safeguards to make sure your information is kept securely. Although we strive to keep member profiles secure, no security measures are absolute or fool-proof, and there is always a possibility that a security breach could occur, resulting in the release of information stored on a member profile.

## Sharing of your personal information

Motilo Limited may share your personal information with third parties in the following ways:

  * We sometimes use agents and service providers to process personal information on our behalf. For example, we use third parties to send postal mail, to process credit card payments and to maintain our IT systems. Where we use agents and service providers to process your personal information, we will ensure that they have adequate security measures in place to keep your personal information safe.
  * If we are required to do so for legal or regulatory purposes or as part of legal proceedings, then we will need to release your personal information.
  * If we decide to sell one or more or our businesses, we may need to give information we hold about you to other companies or individuals as part of this process.
  * We will pass your personal information to carefully selected third parties so that they can contact you about products or services that they think may interest you. We will not pass your information to third parties for marketing purposes if you have told us that you do not want us to do this at the point where you provide your information to us on the website.

In some circumstances we may transfer your personal information to countries outside of the European Economic Area, where data protection safeguards are not as high as they are in the UK. If this occurs we will ensure that adequate procedures are put into place to keep your personal information safe.

## Member profiles

We may allow other users or visitors to our website to see your profile and the information you have provided on the site. We may also allow other users or visitors to our website to look through your community friends lists and other information listed in your profile.

You are free to unsubscribe from the our services and request that we remove your member profile from our databases. However, so that we can resolve disputes, assist with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental requests or investigations, and due to technical constraints, we may need to keep your personal information in certain circumstances.

## Use of our online forums

Any personal information or content that you voluntarily upload to the website or disclose online (on discussion boards, in messages and chat areas, within your public profile page, etc.) becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others. Any content that you submit to the website may be redistributed through the internet and other media channels, and may be viewed by the general public. If you e-mail someone else a video or other special feature from the website, we may use the information you provide about someone else to send that person the requested e-mail.

## Cookies

### What are cookies

Cookies are tiny text files stored on your computer when you visit certain web pages. At Motilo we use cookies to allow you to create & save looks, keep track of what you have in your basket, and to remember you when you return to our site.

To use Motilo’s website, you need to have cookies enabled. If you don't wish to enable cookies, you'll still be able to browse the site and use it for research purposes. Most web browsers have cookies enabled, but see Managing cookies for help to turn them on should you need to.

Please note that cookies can't harm your computer. We don't store personally identifiable information such as credit card details in cookies we create, but we do use encrypted information gathered from them to help improve your experience of the site. For example, they help us to identify and resolve errors, or to determine relevant related products to show you when you're browsing.

We're giving you this information as part of our initiative to comply with recent legislation, and to make sure we're honest and clear about your privacy when using our website.

To make full use of the Motilo experience, your computer, tablet or mobile phone need to accept cookies, as we can only provide you with certain personalised features of this website by using them.

Our cookies don't store sensitive information such as your name, address or payment details: they simply hold the 'key' that, once you're signed in, is associated with this information. However, if you'd prefer to restrict, block or delete cookies from Motilo, or any other website, you can use your browser to do this. Each browser is different, so check the 'Help' menu of your particular browser (or your mobile phone's handset manual) to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

Here's a list of the main cookies we use, and what we use them for, as well as information about third party cookies which we use.

Cookie name | Cookie purpose  
---|---  
PHPSESSID | This cookie helps us recognise you so we can display a welcome message, and provides security when you're using the website around whether you're logged in or not.  
*canvas* | Session data related to the Motilo canvas.  
  
### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to collect information about visitor behaviour on our website. Google Analytics stores information about what pages you visit, how long you are on the site, how you got here and what you click on. This Analytics data is collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of our site and is not tied to personally identifiable information.We therefore do not collect or store your personal information (e.g. your name or address) so this information cannot be used to identify who you are. We have turned on [Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en) to get an idea of our demographics and users' interests. Please see above for how we use this data.

These cookies enable the function of Google Analytics Software. This helps us take and analyse visitor information such as browser usage, new visitor numbers, response to marketing activity and shopping times. That information helps us to improve the website and your shopping experience, and to make our marketing campaigns relevant.

The data stored by these cookies can be seen only by the relevant teams at Motilo and Google and never shows any confidential information.

Cookie name | Cookie purpose  
---|---  
__utmz | stores where a visitor came from (search engine, search keyword, link).  
__utma | stores each user's amount of visits, and the time of the first visit, the previous visit, and the current visit (presumably partly for double checking of this information).  
__utmb  
__utmc | are used to check approximately how long you stay on a site: when a visit starts, and approximately ends (c expires quickly). If you look at cookie state changes (e.g. using firecookie), you will see these change regularly.  
  
### QuBit

These cookies enable the function of analytics software supplied by our business partner Qubit. This software helps us take and analyse visitor information such as browser usage, new visitor numbers, response to marketing activity and shopping times. That information helps us to improve the website and your shopping experience, and to make our marketing campaigns relevant.

The data stored by these cookies can only be seen by the relevant teams at Motilo and Qubit, and never shows any confidential information.

Cookie name | Cookie purpose  
---|---  
_qubitTracker | Assigns a unique id to a visitor.  
_qst | Counts visits.  
_qsst | If it exits, means the current visit has been counted.  
_qPageNum_* | Page number in current visit.  
Qbef | Exit feedback close/submit counts.  
qtab_* | OpenTag session tracking values.  
qubitconsent | Stores whether the user has given consent to use cookies.  
  
### Third party cookies

When you visit Motilo you may notice some cookies that aren't related to Motilo. If you go on to a web page that contains embedded content, for example from YouTube, you may be sent cookies from these websites. We may also use third-party advertising companies to serve or track ads on the website. We don't control the setting of these cookies, so we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them. Motilo does not have access to, or control of, these cookies and/or other data collection tools that may be placed on any advertisement by a third-party, and this Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies and/or other data collection tools by any third party.

## Motilo Share Tools

If you take the opportunity to 'share' Motilo content with friends through social networks – such as Facebook and Twitter - you may be sent cookies from these websites. We don't control the setting of these cookies, so please check those websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them. Access to your:

* **Personal information:** You have the right to request a copy of any personal information that we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. We will just need to ask you to confirm your identity before we disclose any personal information and may charge a £10 fee to process the request to cover our administration costs. Please address requests to the Data Protection Officer, Motilo Limited, 7 Howick Place, London SW1P 1BB.
* **Updates:** We may update this Privacy and Cookies Policy from time to time. Please ensure that you check the Privacy and Cookies Policy regularly for updates.
